What's going on?
何事
Rinon!
りのん
Ichika.
先輩
Kirishima.
霧島君
ここは私に任せて
Leave this to me.
No!
でも
Listen to your elders.
先輩の言うことを聞きなさい
I have a knack for getting out of sticky situations.
こう見えても
逃げ足には自信があるの
檸檬
Lemon!
Ichika.
先輩
All right.
さて
The first alien I met...
初めて出会った宇宙人は
とてもいい子だね
She's a really nice girl.
She's my best friend.
私の親友なの
If you're gonna get in her way...
あの子の邪魔をするというなら
I'm afraid...
すごいこと するわよ
I can't allow that.
檸檬
Lemon!
先輩
Ichika...
Right!
Waiting in the summer
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，请登录www.kamigami.org
日听：秋水无痕 翻译：yaya 校对：小草爱吃梨 Syura 时间轴：小青
I can't go on... This is it...
もう 無理
走れなっ
Kanna?
柑菜ちゃん
Manami?
真奈美さん どうして
What are you doing here?
My husband randomly told me to come out here.
なんか 旦那にいきなりここに来るように言われて
Huh?
はい？
Please drive!
車出してください ストーカーに追われてるんです
I've got a stalker on my heels!
A stalker?
ストーカー？
I'll make quick work of him...
そんなのこのあたしがちゃちゃっと
ストーカー 大きすぎ
Your stalker's huge!
追手は
Can you check?
Still after us.
ついてきてる
Okay.
よしゃ
I wonder if the others are okay.
皆 大丈夫かな
何 もう ついてる頃じゃねえの
Come on.
They should almost be there by now.
うん そうだよね
Yeah, I'm sure of it!
Are you okay, Ichika?
先輩 大丈夫ですか
I'm fine.
私は大丈夫
Once we get over this mountain, we'll be at the train station.
この山を超えれば すぐ駅に出るはずです
Then we can...
そしたら
Oh no! Not again!
そんな また
Ichika!
先輩
Rinna! No, wait.
りんな じゃない
Was that...
これって
my sister?
お姉ちゃん
The anti-field is still active, so this is all I can do.
アンチフィールドがあるから
これぐらいしかできないけど
Go, Ichika.
行きなさい イチカ
Make sure you have no regrets.
せめて 後悔をないように
Thanks.
ありがとう
あいつ まだ
It can still move.
Rinon?
りのん
Rinon!
行きましょう 海人君
Let's go, Kaito.
Okay!
はい
Rinon!
りのん
We can take this where we need to go.
これで 目的地まで行けます
This is my fault.
私のせいで
Because I was so selfish...
私のわがままのせいで
Tanigawa, Ishigaki, Kitahara...
谷川さん
石垣君 北原さん
Lemon, and Rinon too.
檸檬 りのんも
I'm so sorry,
皆 ごめんなさい
everyone.
You shouldn't apologize.
謝ったら ダメです
They all want to see your wish come true.
皆 先輩の願いを叶いたいんです
But...
でも
When we get there, we're gonna find evidence of alien contact,
皆のためにも
その場所に行って 異星人の痕跡を見つけて
and then you won't have to go back into space.
そうすれば 先輩は宇宙に行かなくてすむ
We can all be together.
皆一緒にいられる
Don't worry.
大丈夫 うまくいきますよ
It'll all work out.
If things do work out,
もし 全部がうまく行ったら
maybe I'll be able to go see your planet someday.
いつか 先輩の星にも行けるようになるんですかね
Do you want to?
興味 あるの
そりゃありますよ
Of course.
I want to know where you grew up
先輩がどんなところで暮らしてたのか
and what your family is like. I want to meet them.
家族がどんな人なのか
知りたいし 会いたい
I'd like to introduce you to them.
私も 紹介したいな
What words would you use to introduce me?
何って言って紹介してくれるんですか
バカ
Quiet, you.
I wish I could've introduced you to my parents too.
俺も 先輩を両親に紹介したかったな
But it's fine. I have my sister.
両親のことは もう平気ですから
姉ちゃんもいるし
But sometimes I wish that I could've had more time with everyone together, you know?
でも 思い出とか もっと作っておけばよかったって
思うときもありますけど
That's the reason why I want to use this to leave something permanent behind.
でも だからこいつで
いっぱい いろんなもの残してるんです
It doesn't matter how small it is. At least I won't have any regrets.
ちっちゃな 些細なことでも
後で後悔しないように
You have a lot of memories in this thing, don't you?
ここに 海人君の思い出が詰まってるんだね
Yeah.
はい 哲郎 谷川
Tetsuro, Tanigawa, Kitahara, Lemon, even my sister. Everyone's in here.
北原 檸檬先輩
姉ちゃんも
皆が入ってます
私も
Am I in there?
Of course.
もちろんです
You're the heroine.
ヒロインですから
Ever since I came to this planet, I've been thinking...
この星に来てね
本当によかったと思ってる
皆と出会えて
I'm so glad I got to meet all of you, hang out together, and make a movie.
遊んだり 映画を撮ったり
It's been so much fun.
そういうのが楽しくて
I wish everything would stay this way forever and this summer would never end.
ずっとこのまま 夏が終わんなきゃいいな
なんて 思ったりして
That's how I feel.
I fell in love too.
好きな人もできちゃった
Before I knew it, you became my everything.
いつの間にか 海人君が私の中心になってた
I feel the same way.
俺も 真ん中にいます
It wasn't all fun and games.
楽しいことばかりじゃなかった
There were hard times too.
つらいことだってあった
怒ったり 泣いたり
I got angry, and I cried.
There'll be a lot more to come.
これから先も いろいろありますょ
We might end up fighting one day.
喧嘩だってするかもしれないし
そのときはどうする
What then?
We'll make up.
仲直りします
No matter what.
絶対します
As long as you're in love, you can overcome anything.
好きな気持ちがあれば どんなことだって乗り越えられます
Will you always love me?
ずっと 好きでいてくれる
Of course.
もちろんです
I love you too.
私も 海人君に恋してる
ずっと好きでいる
I'll always love you.
I promise.
約束する
Could you say that one more time?
今のを もう一度お願いします
私は 海人君をずっと好きでいます
I'll...
always love you, Kaito.
だから
So...
...please love me forever too.
ずっと 好きていてね
I will.
はい
I swear I will.
誓います
Of course you'd be stubborn.
さすがに手強い
But don't think I'll just give u—
でもね まだ 諦めるわけには
遅いわよ
Took you long enough.
て 哲郎君
Tetsuro?
悪い 美桜
Bad news, Mio.
ガス欠だ
We're out of gas.
What?!
Are you okay?
大丈夫かい 哲郎君
Tetsuro?
I know that voice.
その声 まさか聡さん
Is that you, Satoshi?
聡さんって 真奈美さんの
You mean that was Manami's...
助けて 聡
Help me, Satoshi!
This thing's gonna get me!
犯される
What's going on?!
何事
I don't know, but I'm not sticking around to find out!
分かんないけど このまま行こうよ
It...
本当に
It really existed.
本当に あった
Then...
じゃあ
Yeah, this is it.
ここよ
This is the place in my memories.
私の中にあるイメージの場所
We made it.
やっと来られた
We finally found it.
やっと見つけた
Thank you, Kaito...
ありがとう
海人君
Everyone...
皆
Let's start looking for proof, Ichika.
先輩
痕跡を探しましょう
何だ
What's that?
That's...
あれは
Is that from the aliens?
あれが異星人の
But this...
でも これは
The way it reacted... That means... But why?
この反応 やっぱり
でも なんで
Ichika...
せ 先輩
What is this?
これ 何なんですか
You can see this?
見えるの
What?
はい
だって これは 私のイメージの中の
But this is the image in my mind.
治療に使った私のセル
I used my cells to heal him.
This is the proof we need!
痕跡って
これ
Yeah.
Ichika!
先輩
No...
そんな
Why?
なんで
We came all this way!
せっかく せっかく
This sucks!
Is that the place Ichika and the others were heading to?
あれは イチカたちが向かってた場所
Did they break the spacial shielding?
空間のシールトが破られたの
This is bad, Ichika.
だめよ イチカ
Hurry and get out of there.
はやく そこから逃げなさい
海人君
Kaito!
Ichika!
先輩
Stop! Don't hurt him!
やめて
その人を傷つけないで
I promise I won't run away!
もう 逃げたりしないから
No, Ichika!
ダメです 先輩
Stop! Please.
やめて
お願い
Please stop.
もう やめて
Ichika!
先輩
I'm sorry, Kaito.
ごめんなさい 海人君
I can't do this anymore...
やっぱり
私 もう
What are—
何を
It's my fault.
私のせいで
You're in danger! Everyone's in danger because of me.
海人君を 皆を危険な目にあわせて
It's all because I was so selfish!
全部 私のわがままです
No!
違う
No, Ichika!
違いますよ 先輩
I already told you.
言ったでしょう
They all...
皆 少なくとも 俺は
Well, at least I...
don't think of it that way!
そんなふうに思ってない
If anything, I'm the selfish one here.
むしろ これは俺のわがままです
I don't want to let you go!
行かせたくない 先輩を
Thank you, Kaito.
ありがとう
海人君
Ichika!
先輩
I...
私 この星に来たこと後悔しかけてた
almost regretted coming to this planet.
I got you all wound up in my selfish plans,
私の勝手な思いが 皆を巻き込んで
and in the end, nothing came of it.
結局 何も成し遂げられなくて
But now I understand.
でも やっと分かった
We all found each other because we wanted something to happen.
私達 何かを始めたいと思って
お互いを見つけた
ちゃんと見つけることができた
We were able to find each other.
I will always have these feelings within me.
私の中に生まれたこの思いは
ずっと続くわ
They'll never go away.
絶対に消えないって
That's what I believe.
信じられる
But...
そんなの
I love you, Kaito.
大好きだよ
海人君
俺だって
I love you... too.
ずっと ずっと
I'll always...
Ichi—
先
I'll come get you!
迎えに行きます
絶対に行きます
I swear I will!
うん 待ってる
I'll be waiting.
Ichika!
先輩！！！
海
Kai—
あれから
I wonder
how long it's been.
どれほどのときが流れたのでしょう
But thank you for finding it.
でも
見つけてくれてありがとう
This is...
これは イングローブから直接聞こえる
I can hear it directly from the In-Grove...
I made an emergency landing on this planet,
私は宇宙船を乗って
The genetic memory of our ancestors has been released?
受け継がれた先祖のデータが解放されて
after I had trouble with my spaceship, and someone here saved me.
この星に不時着して
この星の人に助けてもらいました
Before I knew it, I had fallen in love.
いつしか その人は私の大切な人になって
But this is a remote planet where contact with the locals is strictly forbidden.
でも この星は原生住民との接触が許されない辺境惑星
Help will soon be on the way.
まもなく 迎えがやってきます
I imagine my memories on this planet will be sealed to maintain secrecy.
秘密保持のため
この星での記憶は封鎖されてしまうでしょう
でも
Even so, I wanted to leave some proof behind of the time we spent together.
どうしても
あの人との思い出を残しておきたかった
私の記憶が無くなっても
Even if my memories faded... Even if I couldn't remember...
思い出せなくても
I wanted to leave something behind.
残しておきたかったの
Thank you for finding it.
見つけてくれて ありがとう
I pray that at least my memories will live on in you.
私の記憶が せめて あなたの思い出になりますよね
お願い 忘れないで
Please don't forget.
I won't forget.
忘れないよ
I could never forget.
忘れられるわけない
ずっと待ってるね
I'll always be waiting.
All we had
それは ほんの数ヶ月の出来事
were a few months.
一夏の出来事
All we had was a single summer.
あの時の私達は
Back then, we still hadn't done anything,
まだ 何もしてなくて
でも 何かしたいと思っていて
but we wanted to.
And that's when Ichika showed up...
そんなとき イチカ先輩が現れて
and turned our summer into something special.
私達の夏を 特別にしてくれたんです
喜びや悲しみ
Joy and sorrow.
It was all there...
すべてが詰まってる
...in that summer.
あの夏を
We...
俺達は
Episode Twelve
Waiting there, in the summer.
...will never forget that summer.
あの夏を 忘れない
Castle Park
Here, Tetsuro.
哲郎 これ
A girl in the class next door asked me to give this to you.
隣のクラスの子に頼まれた
Why'd you take it?
受け取るなよ
What else could I do?
仕方ないでしょう
Make sure you give her an answer.
ちゃんと返事しなさいよ
Actually, just get a damn girlfriend.
っていうか いい加減 彼女作れ
Yeah, but...
つってもさあ
Mio's good enough, isn't she?
美桜でいいでしょう 美桜で
I wouldn't mind.
ウェルカムだよ
Well, yeah, but...
いや まあ それは だな
What's so funny, Kai?
笑ってんじゃねえよ 海
Okay, see you later.
じゃあ また明日
Take care.
気をつけてな
'Kay.
All right, see ya.
じゃあ 俺も
またね
See ya.
Hey...
なあ
Let's go home.
帰ろう
おう
Yeah.
Huh?
あれ 鍵 締め忘れたっけ
Did I forget to lock it?
Welcome home.
お帰りなさい
Sis!
お姉さん
I'm back.
ただいま帰りました
How was Bolivia?
どうだった ボリビア
It was a lot of work, but it was fun too.
大変だったわ
でも 楽しかった
That's good.
よかった
Oh yeah...
はい おみやげ
Here are some souvenirs.
趣味悪くない
I question your taste.
The doll is famous over there for being able to grant wishes.
あら 願いが叶う人形って向こうじゃ有名なのよ
This is for Ichika!
で これがイチカちゃんの分
Speaking of which, where is she?
そういえば イチカちゃんは
She... well...
せ 先輩は その
Her time abroad ran out.
留学期間が終わってさ 故郷に戻ったんだ
She went back home.
Really? That's a shame.
ええ そうなの
残念だわ
We could send it to her.
じゃあ 送ってあげてよ
You know her address, right?
住所は知ってるんでしょう
うん そうする
Yeah.
Let's do that.
Wishes, huh?
願い事か
へえ？
You're transferring away?
転校ですか
Yeah.
ええ 家の事情でね
Family stuff.
But you can't leave too.
そんな 檸檬先輩までいなくっ
So when are you transferring?
それで いつ転校するんですか
今から
Right now.
Huh?
It's not a farewell gift or anything, but this is for you guys.
餞別というわけではないけど
あなたたちに
What is this?
なんです
These are...
これ
Film reels?
フィルム
Why...
なんで
Lemon?
檸檬先輩
That was a truly wonderful summer.
本当 素敵な夏だったわ
But you know...
でもね
The movie is still incomplete.
映画は未完成
You're the one who has to put the finishing touches on the last scene.
ラストシーンを飾るのは あなたよ
Sorry about this, Kai.
悪いな 海
We came over all of a sudden.
急に 押しかけて
It's fine.
いいよ 今日 お姉さん遅いし
My sister will be home late today.
It's been a while since we all came here together again.
でも 久しぶりだね
皆でここに集まるの
じゃあ 電気消すね
I'm gonna turn off the lights, okay?
Okay.
Kai.
海
Are you okay?
いいか
Here goes.
回すよ
Yamano Lemon
Incomplete Version
I looked for the reason why I fell in love
and tried solemn words
Once I realized my feelings,
the threads had gotten hopelessly tangled up
If I'd been able to say it without hesitation
you wouldn't have to cry now
We paint a picture of feelings that pierce the clouds
Forever we will remember the scent of summer on the wind
My memories of when I was with someone
put color into my life, drop by drop, like the evening rain
People say that when someone dies, they go to Heaven.
人が死んだら
The things beyond my lens
天国に行けるという
But I don't think that's the case.
でも 僕はそうとは思わない
seems like an otherworldly reflection
When someone dies, I think that person journeys into people's hearts.
死んだ人間は きっと誰かの心へと旅立つのだ
When I realized the feelings I'd lost
They live on as a memory.
思い出となって 生き続けるのだ
our time began
けれど
Of course...
memories eventually fade with time.
それも やがては消えていく
That's why people want to leave something behind.
だから 人は何かを残したいと願うのだ
No matter how I tried to balance our love on scales
So others won't forget them. So we'll remember them.
忘れてしまわないように
it never worked out
忘れないように
I'll keep filming.
僕は カメラを回し続ける
The sun scorches
I'll record the continuation to what I already have
フィルムに焼き付けたあの夏を
the clouds with its rays
of that summer.
その続きを
and I wish for its warmth and brightness with every fiber of my being
I remember that summer like it was yesterday
and all my memories from my childhood
Let us take them both and let them fly far over the ocean
Filming on Okinawa
They're playing the movie again this year.
今年もやってんだこの映画
You mean the one the alumni left behind?
卒業生が残してたってやつ
I saw it last year.
俺去年見たよ すごかった
It was pretty good.
There were spaceships, robots, and a lot of special effects.
宇宙船とか メカとか
特撮ばりばりで
And the heroine's a hottie.
あと ヒロインが美人
That all you care about?
結局はそこかよ
You've got nowhere to stay?
住む場所がない
That's right.
そ そうなの
Then how about you stay at my place?
だったら 俺の家に行きませんか
I live on my own,
俺 一人暮らしだし
so I have spare rooms.
家に部屋余ってますから
So what happened to your spaceship?
で 宇宙船はどうしたんですか
What? It broke?
は？壊れた
Again?
また？
皆さん 応援 ありがとうございました
ありがとうございました